让我们考虑一个更复杂的案例。
Let’s consider a more complex case.
我想从这个特定的X值开始。
I want to start at this particular X value.
我想完成这个特定的X值。
I want to finish at this particular X value.
但是，介于两者之间，我想访问这个X值和这个X值。
But, in between, I wanted to visit this X value and this X value.
我将这些中间点称为通过点。
I refer to these intermediate points as via points.
有时，它也被称为路点。
Sometimes, it’s also referred to as way
如果一个机器人要做这个特定的动作，我们的轨迹就会出现问题
If a robot is going to do this particular motion, we have a problem in that the trajectory
不顺利。
is not smooth.
在每个点处，速度突然从一个值变为另一个值。
At each of the points, the velocity abruptly changes from one value to another.
在这里，速度在增加。
Here, the velocity is increasing.
片刻之后，速度在下降。
A moment later, the velocity is decreasing.
我们解决这个问题的方法是引入所谓的混合。
The way we get around this problem is to introduce what are called blends.
所以在这里，我们有这些点之间的运动和红色，它显示了混合
So here, we have the motion between these points and in red, it’s shown the blend
相。
phase.
现在，我们在这里引入一条保持连续性的平滑数学曲线。
Now, this is where we introduce a smooth mathematical curve which maintains continuity.
因此，最初，我们加速到曲线并前往X2。
So, initially, we accelerate on to the curve and head towards X2.
当我们接近X2时，我们开始转换到我们需要的速度到下一个
When we get near X2, we start to transition in to the velocity we require on to the next
路径。
path.
因此，我们将速度转换为设定的时间段，超过所谓的加速度
So, we transition our velocity over a set period, over what’s called the acceleration
间隔。
interval.
因此，我们的路径现在由具有抛物线或更高阶多项式的线速度段组成
So, our path now consists of segments of linear velocity with parabolic or higher-order polynomial
混合将它们连接在一起。
blends to join them together.
我们可以根据三个部分来考虑这项议案。
We can consider the motion in terms of three segments.
第一段从第1点到第2点，第2段从第2点到第2点
The first segment gets us from point 1 to point 2, second segment from point 2 to point
3等等。
3 and so on.
因为你现在可能已经注意到机器人实际上没有进入通道
Because you probably noticed by now that the robot isn’t actually getting to the via
点。
points.
它越来越接近X2，然后它将转向前进的道路
It’s getting close to X2 and then it’s going to turn to get on to the path to head
走向X3。
towards X3.
所以，它错过了X2然后实际上也错过了X3。
So, it misses X2 and then actually misses X3 as well.
现在，这只是一个折衷。
Now, this is just a bit of a trade off.
如果加速时间非常小，那么我们将非常接近通孔点，但是
If the acceleration time is very small, then we will go very close to the via points, but
加速度会很高。
the acceleration will be very high.
我们将不得不前往X2，然后非常非常快地改变我们的速度
We’re going to have to head towards X2 and then very, very quickly change our velocity
我们需要前往X3的速度。
in to the velocity we need to head towards X3.
如果加速时间很长，那么机器人的加速度要低得多，但是
If the acceleration time is large, then the acceleration of the robot is much lower, but
我们将错过更多的通过积分。
we’re going to miss the via points by a larger amount.
这是精度和加速度之间的基本工程权衡。
This is a fundamental engineering trade off between accuracy and acceleration.
让我们创建一个带有via点的轨迹。
Let’s create a trajectory with via points.
我们要访问的第一点的值为10。
The first point we want to visit has got a value of 10.
我访问的最后一点的值为30。
The last point that I visit has got a value of 30.
并且，我将设置为40,10和最后一个。
And, the via points I’m going to set as 40, 10 and the last one.
为了计算带有通孔点的轨迹，我使用了工具箱函数mstraj和它
To compute a trajectory with via points, I used the Toolbox function mstraj and it’s
得到了很多争论。
got rather a lot of arguments.
第一个参数是通过点。
First argument is the via points.
下一个参数是我们移动的速度，它将是每个单位的一个单位
The next argument is the velocity at which we move, and it’s going to be one unit per
第二。
second.
第三个参数我将暂时设置为null。
The third argument I’m going to set to null for the time being.
而且，我将把我们想要访问的第一个位置放入。
And, I’m going to put in the first location that we want to visit.
我要把时间间隔放进去，我要加速加速时间。
I’m going to put in the time interval and I’m going to put in the acceleration time.
而且，这是我们的轨迹。
And, here is our trajectory.
我们已经从10上升到40，然后回到10到30。
We’ve gone from 10 up to 40, back down to 10 and up to 30.
现在，让我们看一下当我们调整一些参数时会发生什么。
Now, let’s look at what happens when we adjust some of the parameters.
我要做的第一件事就是增加加速时间。
The first thing I’m going to do is to increase the acceleration time.
所以，我要把它从2增加到4，我们可以看到轨迹已经变成了
So, I’m going to increase it from 2 to 4 and we can see that the trajectory has become
更圆润。
more rounded.
并且，我们还可以看到轨迹错过通孔点的距离增加了。
And, we can also see the distance by which the trajectory misses the via points has increased.
我可以进一步增加加速时间，把它增加到8，我们可以再次看到
I can increase the acceleration time even more, put it up to 8 and we can see again
因为加速度更加温和，所以轨迹更加圆润
that the trajectory is much more rounded because the acceleration is much gentler but, the
轨迹和通孔点之间的距离进一步增加。
distance between the trajectory and the via points is increased even further.
如果我将加速时间设置为0，我们确切地到达了通过点，但轨迹将是
If I set the acceleration time to 0, we exactly reach the via points but the trajectory will
是不连续的。
be discontinuous.
通孔点的加速度无限大。
The acceleration will be infinite at the via points.
让我们回到更温和的东西。
Let’s go back to something a little bit more gentle.
而现在，我要做的是提高我们沿着轨迹移动的速度。
And now, what I’m going to do is to increase the velocity at which we move along the trajectory.
您现在可以看到此轨迹需要将近90秒才能执行。
You can see right now that this trajectory takes nearly 90 seconds to execute.
所以，我要将我们沿着轨迹移动的速度加倍，改变速度
So, I’m going to double the speed at which we move along the trajectory, change the velocity
从1到2，现在我们在不到50秒的时间内执行轨迹。
from 1 to 2, and now we execute the trajectory in just under 50 seconds.
我要做的最后一件事是删除速度规范并替换
The last thing that I’m going to do is to remove the velocity specification and replace
它有时间规格。
it with a time specification.
我要说我不关心速度，但我确实关心时间。
I’m going to say that I don’t care about velocity, but I do care about the time.
而且，我想指定细分的时间。
And, I want to specify the times of the segments.
我希望第一段持续10秒。
I want the first segment to last for 10 seconds.
我希望第二段持续30秒。
I want the second segment to last for 30 seconds.
并且，我希望最后一段能够持续20秒。
And, I want the last segment to last for 20 seconds.
现在，轨迹看起来像这样。
And now, the trajectory looks like this.